export const PICTUREMAKINGA2021 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Select a painter from the following artists.",
A: "E. Owusu Dartey",
B: "K. K. Broni",
C: "Oku Ampofo",
D: "R. C. Ekem",
answer: "C. Oku Ampofo",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Artists use horizontal lines in pictures to portray",
A: "anger and agitation.",
B: "direction and movement.",
C: "tension and confusion.",
D: "tranquility and repose.",
answer: "D. tranquility and repose.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. A picture plane positioned vertically is technically referred to as",
A: "folio.",
B: "landscape.",
C: "portrait.",
D: "quarto.",
answer: "C. portrait.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. One major characteristic of a newsprint is that, it is",
A: "highly absorbent.",
B: "multi coloured.",
C: "thickly coated.",
D: "very smooth.",
answer: "A. highly absorbent.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Masking tapes are stretched over the edges of screens to",
A: "allow penetration of ink.",
B: "allow squeegeeing.",
C: "prevent printing ink from seeping.",
D: "strengthen the edges of the screen.",
answer: "C. prevent printing ink from seeping.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Which of the following statements is true about direct and block prints?",
A: "Both produce very sharp edges",
B: "Their textures are from natural objects",
C: "There are no designs on their surfaces",
D: "They are both types of relief printing",
answer: "D. They are both types of relief printing",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The process of printing with silk screens is",
A: "engraving.",
B: "etching.",
C: "lithography.",
D: "serigraphy.",
answer: "D. serigraphy.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Aesthetics is associated with the study of",
A: "beauty.",
B: "colour.",
C: "proportion.",
D: "symbolism.",
answer: "A. beauty.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following processes is applied to a finished water-colour painting?",
A: "Mounting",
B: "Scumbling",
C: "Spongin",
D: "Washes",
answer: "A. Mounting",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The main difference between warer-colour and gouache paintings is that, water-colour is",
A: "blurry.",
B: "glossy.",
C: "opaque.",
D: "transparent.",
answer: "D. transparent.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Paint brushes are stored after use with the tip",
A: "downwards.",
B: "in linseed oil.",
C: "in soapy walter.",
D: "upwards.",
answer: "D. upwards.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. A still life is said to have variety when",
A: "all the objects have many colours.",
B: "most of the objects have shape and coloured,",
C: "the objects are related and similar.",
D: "the objects differ in size, shape and colour.",
answer: "D. the objects differ in size, shape and colour.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Which of these principles is employed to create visual tension in art?",
A: "Dominance",
B: "Rhythm",
C: "Opposition",
D: "Transition",
answer: "C. Opposition",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Select a vehicle from the following options.",
A: "Glue",
B: "Resin",
C: "Water",
D: "Wax",
answer: "C. Water",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. A picture maker employs chiaroscuro to make paintings appear",
A: "dark and flat.",
B: "flat and vibrant.",
C: "realistic and smooth.",
D: "solid and realistic.",
answer: "D. solid and realistic.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. In painting, reflected light is usually the",
A: "colour of light that dominates,",
B: "light from one object onto the other.",
C: "point of greatest brilliance.",
D: "receding middle tone,",
answer: "C. point of greatest brilliance.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Which of the following tools are correetly paired in respect of function?",
A: "Hand roller and palette knife",
B: "Iland roller and squeegee",
C: "Palette knife and squeegee",
D: "Squeegee and spatula",
answer: "C. Palette knife and squeegee",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. A major characteristic of glass mosaic is its",
A: "colour and mass.",
B: "form and opacity.",
C: "overlapping forms and colours,",
D: "regular shapes and texture,",
answer: "A. colour and mass.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. A picture built on a flat board with pieces of veneer is termed",
A: "Collage.",
B: "Marquetry.",
C: "Marouflage.",
D: "Mosaic.",
answer: "B. Marquetry.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The effect of light on the surfaces of objects was the main focus of the",
A: "Cubists.",
B: "Expressionists.",
C: "Fauvists.",
D: "Impressionists.",
answer: "D. Impressionists.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Leonardo da Vinci is associated with",
A: "alla prima.",
B: "contraposto.",
C: "sfumato.",
D: "tenebrism.",
answer: "C. sfumato.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The focus of the ancient Egyptian painting was on",
A: "cultural importance of the Pharaoh,",
B: "life in the hereafter of the Pharaoh.",
C: "life of the queens.",
D: "transportation on Nile river,",
answer: "B. life in the hereafter of the Pharaoh.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The tool that creates a gradual blend between multiple colours in photoshop is",
A: "dodge.",
B: "gradient.",
C: "sharpen.",
D: "smudge.",
answer: "B. gradient.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Study drawings are very important in",
A: "capturing the fleeting events.",
B: "capturing smaller objects.",
C: "developing abstract ideas.",
D: "understanding the structure of objects.",
answer: "D. understanding the structure of objects.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Angular perspective is also identified as",
A: "aerial perspective.",
B: "oblique perspective.",
C: "one-point perspective.",
D: "two-point perspective.",
answer: "B. oblique perspective.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. To cost a mosaic for sale, it is essential to consider",
A: "current market price.",
B: "demand and function.",
C: "tools and materials used.",
D: "type of customers.",
answer: "B. demand and function.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Which of the following is a contemporary function of body painting?",
A: "Advertising",
B: "Healing",
C: "Protection",
D: "Spirituality",
answer: "A. Advertising",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The fundamental requirement for an art exhibition is the preparation of the",
A: "catalogue.",
B: "hall.",
C: "refreshment.",
D: "works.",
answer: "D. works.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. An artist working on mosaic would require",
A: "canvas.",
B: "plywood.",
C: "scraps.",
D: "veneer,",
answer: "C. scraps.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Which picture making technique involves burning on surfaces?",
A: "Engraving",
B: "Parquetry",
C: "Ross Pyrography",
D: "Scraffito",
answer: "C. Pyrography",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. A composition painted with the complementary of green symbolizes",
A: "aggression.",
B: "growth.",
C: "peace.",
D: "tenderness.",
answer: "C. peace.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The first step in the preparation of a panel for painting is",
A: "glazing.",
B: "priming.",
C: "sizing.",
D: "washing.",
answer: "B. priming.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The usual way of rendering the human head in silhouette for recognition is the",
A: "back view.",
B: "front view.",
C: "full view.",
D: "side view.",
answer: "D. side view.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Which of the following processes is applied in the preparation of a ground for mural?",
A: "Scumbling",
B: "Sizing",
C: "Washing",
D: "Varnishing",
answer: "B. Sizing",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Most suitable paper for water-colour painting in the option is",
A: "bond paper.",
B: "butter paper.",
C: "cartridge.",
D: "newsprint.",
answer: "C. cartridge.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The symbolic meaning of green in the traditional Ghanaian society is",
A: "beauty.",
B: "fertility.",
C: "purity.",
D: "wealth.",
answer: "B. fertility.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Select a hue from the following options.",
A: "Black",
B: "Brown",
C: "Pink",
D: "Yellow",
answer: "D. Yellow",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Which of the following is vital in the sale of a painting?",
A: "Advertisement",
B: "Labour",
C: "Skills",
D: "Time",
answer: "A. Advertisement",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. A spot on the horizon towards which parallel lines appear to recede is the",
A: "centre of vision.",
B: "picture plane.",
C: "sky line.",
D: "vanishing point.",
answer: "D. vanishing point.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Select the colour combination that is best used to depict both sunrise and sunset skies.",
A: "Green and blue",
B: "Orange and yellow",
C: "Violet and green",
D: "Yellow and green",
answer: "B. Orange and yellow",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]